Mss.B.H97p
American Philosophical Society
James Hutchinson papers, 1771-1928
Mss.B.H97p
American Philosophical Society
0.25 Linear feet 106 items
The collection includes letters between Hutchinson and his uncle Israel Pemberton, written while Hutchinson was a student of medicine in London. There are also 12 tickets of admission to medical lectures in Philadelphia and London, including one given by William Hunter, and 3 unused cards of admission to Hutchinson's own lectures. Miscellaneous items include Hutchinson's marriage certificate; genealogical data on the Hutchinson, Hare, and Pemberton families; and stock certificates, 1857-1872, of the McKean and Elk Land and Improvement Company. Materials dated post-1793 are to and from Hutchinson family members.
106 items.
Hutchinson, James, 1752-1793
Box 1
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Presented by S. Pemberton Hutchinson and accessioned, 1962. See in-house shelf list for additional accession sources and dates.
Biographical/Historical note
James Hutchinson (1752-1793, APS 1779), physician and surgeon, Surgeon General of Pennsylvania, 1778-1784, was born in Makefield Township, Bucks County, Pennsylvania. Hutchinson was the son of Quaker farmer and stonemason Randall Hutchinson and his wife Katherine Milnor. In 1771 at the age of fifteen, Hutchinson was apprenticed to the apothecaries Moses Bartram (1732-1809, APS 1766) and Isaac Bartram (1725-1801, APS 1759). He became the pupil of Philadelphia physician Cadwalader Evans. He served as apothecary of the Pennsylvania Hospital (1773-1775) and earned a bachelor’s degree in Medicine from the College of Philadelphia. In 1776 he completed a twelve-month residency in London under John Fothergill at St. Bartholomew’s Hospital, preparing for a surgical career. After the outbreak of the American War of Independence, Hutchinson returned home in early 1777 via France, carrying dispatches from Benjamin Franklin to the Continental Congress. He was elected a physician at the Pennsylvania Hospital in May 1777. Hutchinson tended the wounded soldiers from the battle of Germantown and inoculated more than 3,000 soldiers at Valley Forge against smallpox. He was an original member of the Philadelphia Medical Society and a trustee of the University of the State of Pennsylvania after 1779. Hutchinson was a founder the College of Physicians of Philadelphia in 1787. He was elected a member of the American Philosophical Society in 1779, and served as Secretary from 1782-1793.
Although a member of the Society of Friends, the American War of Independence caused Hutchinson to question Quaker pacifist convictions. The twenty-three year old medical student wrote in December 1775, “I have too great an affection for my Country not to feel its distresses.” For his efforts caring for Continental troops, Hutchinson was named senior surgeon of the Flying Camp of the Middle Department of the Continental Army on December 1, 1777 and appointed surgeon of the Pennsylania State Navy in 1778. He was disowned by the Society of Friends on February 26, 1779 for quasi-military service.
Hutchinson’s sense of civic duty advanced in tandem with his professional stature. In 1779 he was reappointed to the staff of the Pennsylvania Hospital, where he specialized in surgery and obstetrics. He was also appointed one of the Port of Philadelphia’s quarantine physicians. After establishing the College of Physicians of Philadelphia in 1787, he served first as secretary, then as censor, responsible for maintaining ethical standards and professional conduct among the city’s doctors. As a trustee of the University of the State of Pennsylvania, he worked to revive medical education, and taught chemistry and materia medica there after 1789. Later he became professor of Chemistry at the University of Pennsylvania, created by the union of the old College of Philadelphia and the University of the State of Pennsylvania. Meanwhile, Hutchinson, motivated by a sense of civic responsibility and revolutionary fervor, became increasing active in politics. In 1780, he served briefly in the Pennsylvania Assembly, although he soon decided that he was not interested in being an elected official. An anti-Federalist, Hutchinson was a strong supporter of Thomas Jefferson (1743-1825, APS 1780) and the founder of the Pennsylvania Democratic Society in 1793. He wrote lampoons and letters for the press, corresponded with other Democrats and kept abreast of Federalist schemes. He also served on a committee that received the French ambassador Edmond Charles Genet, who sought to galvanize American opinion in support of the French revolutionary government and against Great Britain.
Ultimately, Hutchinson’s sense for responsibility for his fellow citizens was manifest as Hutchinson moved among his patients during the Yellow Fever epidemic of 1793. He caught the contagion on August 30, and died one week later. His death focused public debate, led by Benjamin Rush, on the cause and treatment of Yellow fever.
Hutchinson was twice married, first to Lydia Biddle in 1779 and then to Sydney Howell in 1786. He and Howell had two sons, and a daughter, who died in infancy.
Scope and Contents Note
The collection of James Hutchinson’s papers consists primarily but not exclusively of correspondenc, between the late eighteenth-century Philadelphia physician and a number of family members, political friends, and professional associates.
The largest and earliest series of letters (seventeen) is between Hutchinson and his uncle Israel Pemberton, written while Hutchinson was a student of medicine in London. Other momentos of his student years are twelve tickets of admission to medical lectures in Philadelphia and London, including one given by William Hunter. There are also three unused cards of admission to Hutchinson's own lectures on chemistry at the University of Pennsylvania. Another series of nine letters from Hutchinson’s friend, the Philadelphia lawyer/Pennsylvania legislator Charles Pettit, date from 1785-1786 and reflect concerns of the early Republic, especially mechanisms to handle the national debt.
In addition to these several groups of letters, there are individual pieces of correspondence, spanning the period from Hutchinson’s student days through the end of his career. These include letters of reference and professional certifications signed by his mentors American physicians Benjamin Rush (April 9, 1773), Cadwalder Evans (April 19, 1772) and English physician John Fothergill (December 9, 1776). Individual items of professional correspondence include a February 7, 1793 request from the War Department to examine a Revolutionary veteran to “certify the nature of his disability;” and a August 24, 1793 report from Dr. Rush “On [a] malignant fever [that ] has lately appeared in Water Street of our city.” There is also ample evidence of Hutchinson’s radical democratic and abolitionist politics. These include a November 6, 1792 certificate of membership in the Pennsylvania Society for the Abolition of Slavery, as well as an August 1, 1793 letter from Charles Caldwell, requesting that Hutchinson, the founder of the Pennsylvania Democratic Society, recommend him for membership.
Other miscellaneous items include Hutchinson's marriage certificates to Lydia Biddle and Sydney Howell, genealogical data on the Hutchinson, Hare, and Pemberton families and stock certificates, 1857-1872, of the McKean and Elk Land and Improvement Company. Materials dated post-1793 are to and from Hutchinson family members. One twentieth-century family letter from S. Pemberton Hutchinson to James P. Hutchinson also sheds light on the provenance of the collection, suggesting that the papers be donated to the American Philosophical Society of which Hutchinson was the Secretary from 1782-1793.
Early American History Note
The James Hutchinson Papers detail this prominent Philadelphian’s medical education and life. The collection includes records of Hutchinson’s formal education, lectures he either attended or delivered, and his travels throughout London to advance his career. The documents from the American Revolution provide interesting commentary on events happening in Philadelphia and how the Revolution affected Quakers.
His letters from London often summarize the lectures he attended. Hutchinson’s letters to his uncle, Israel Pemberton, often provide additional commentary on life and current events. One letter, for instance, gives details on his voyage crossing the Atlantic, including information on catching fish and encountering an iceberg.
The collection also contains letters sent to Israel Pemberton from other individuals who had sent their letters in the same packet as James Hutchinson. Some of the letters were written in the midst of the American Revolution as James sought a way to return to Pennsylvania from London. Physician John Fothergill was among those who helped Hutchinson return to America.
Hutchinson’s Revolutionary War correspondence is extensive and often discusses the controversies of the revolutionary Pennsylvania government, especially as it affected Quakers, such as the suspension of habeas corpus and the exile of a group of pacifist Quakers, including Israel Pemberton, to Winchester, Virginia. Hutchinson also interacted with the military and served as a volunteer to treat wounded soldiers. There is a letter sent by Mary Pemberton to Israel in this collection as well.
Additional documents chronicle Hutchinson’s life, including a marriage certificate, land dealings (including a tract of land granted to him by James Wilkinson), letters on politics and medicine, and various receipts. Hutchinson was a regular correspondent with Charles Pettit when Pettit represented New York in the Continental Congress.
Related Archival Materials note
APS also possesses the James Hutchinson's diary from 1777 (Mss.B.H97d.1), which chronicles Hutchinson's trans-Atlantic passage during the American Revolution.
Bache, Benjamin Franklin, 1769-1798; Banks, Joseph, Sir, 1743-1820; Bartram, Isaac, 1725-1801; Biddle, Clement, 1740-1814; Caldwell, Charles, 1772-1853; Corbyn, Thomas; Ellicott, Andrew, 1754-1820; Ewing, John, 1732-1802; Fothergill, John, 1712-1780; Greene, Nathanael, 1742-1786; Hare family.; Hiester, Joseph, 1752-1832; Hunter, William, 1718-1783; Hutchinson family.; Hutchinson, Charles Hare, 1833-1902; Lettsom, John Coakley, 1744-1815; McKean and Elk Land and Improvement Co.; Paulmier, Charles Francois Adrien le,chevalier d'Annemours,1742-1809.; Pemberton family.; Pemberton, Israel, 1715-1779; Pettit, Charles, 1736-1806; Rush, Benjamin, 1746-1813; Townsend, John, 1759-1826; American Revolution; Americans Abroad; Education; Educational Material; Family Correspondence; Genealogies.; General Correspondence; Marriage and Family Life; Marriage certificates.; Medicine; Medicine -- Study and teaching -- England -- London -- 18th century.; Medicine -- Study and teaching -- Pennsylvania -- Philadelphia -- 18th century.; Miscellaneous; Philadelphia History; Religion; Stock certificates.
- Papers
  - Tickets of admission for James Hutchinson to attend medical lectures of: William Shippen, Jr., Dr. Kuhn, Benjamin Rush, and 3 blank tickets to attend the lectures of James Hutchinson to attend lectures of John Hunter and Christopher Collis, in England, 1771-179_; 2-1/2x3-3/4 and 3x4; University of Pennsylvania
    Scope and Contents note
    Printed D. filled in in ms. S. 12 items.
  - Papers, chiefly on medicine, and many letters addressed to Israel Pemberton, 1771-1928; Hutchinson, James, 1752-1793
    D. 106 items. Various sizes. presented by S. Pemberton Hutchinson, via his sister, Mrs. Henry S. Drinker; June 5, 1962. Table of contents available.
  - Letter to Israel Pemberton, Philadelphia, March 30, 1772; Hutchinson, James, 1752-1793
    Barbados, Xerox of A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Mutilated. From original in the Quaker Collection of the Haverford College Library. News of Charley, their safe arrival, and events in Barbados.
  - Certification that James Hutchinson knows how to mix medicines as an apothecary, 1773; 5-1/4x7; Bartram, Isaac
    A.D.S. 1p.
  - Certification that James Hutchinson attended his lectures on chemistry at the University of Pennsylvania medical school, April 9, 1773; 7-1/2x6; Rush, Benjamin, 1746-1813
  - Letter to the Physicians of the Hospital, April 19, 1773; 6-1/2x8; Evans, Cadwallader, 1762-1841
    A.L.S. 1p. Recommends James Hutchinson for duty as hospital apothecary.
  - Letter to Israel Pemberton, Philadelphia, July 10, [1775]; 8x6-1/4; Hutchinson, James, 1752-1793
    Newcastle, Delaware, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Thanks him for favors and hopes to sail from the Capes of the Delaware tomorrow.
  - Letter to Israel Pemberton, Philadelphia, July 11, 1775; 8-1/2x6-1/2; Hutchinson, James, 1752-1793
    A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Hopes to sail for England. Dr. Kuhn is sea-sick.
  - Letter to Israel Pemberton, Philadelphia, August 30, 1775; 12-1/4x7-1/2; Hutchinson, James, 1752-1793
    London, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. Description of England and his reception there. Refers to various friends, among whom is Fothergill.
  - Letter to [Thomas] Parks [Parke], Philadelphia, Sept. 10, 1775; 9x7-1/2; Lettsom, John Coakley, 1744-1815
    London, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Is pleased with James Hutchinson. Wonders why his letters miscarry. Friendly letter.
  - Ticket of admission for James Hutchinson for six months, Oct. 3, 1775; 3x5; St. Bartholomew's Hospital (London, England)
    Printed D. filled in in ms. S.: Percivall Pott and 2 others. 1p.
  - Letter to [Mrs.] Katherine [Rickey Hutchinson] Milnor, Pennsylvania, Dec. 20, 1775; 8-1/2x7-1/4; Hutchinson, James, 1752-1793
    London, A.L.S. 3p. and add. Misses his Philadelphia friends and hopes relations with England improve. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Israel Pemberton, Philadelphia, December 20, 1775; 13x8; Hutchinson, James, 1752-1793
    London, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. His medical studies in England. Refers to Fothergill, John and William Hunter, Pott. News of America and England.
  - Certification that James Hutchinson has attended Practice 12 months, [1776]; 15x11-1/4x; St. Bartholomew's Hospital (London, England)
    Printed D. filled in in ms. S.: Percivall Pott. 1p.
  - Letter to Israel Pemberton, April 7, 1776; 13x7-3/4; Hutchinson, James, 1752-1793
    London, A.L.S. 4p., end. Copy. His study of medicine. Thinks U. of P. is best in physics. Refers to Pott and John Hunter as teacher. Refers to Fothergill. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Israel Pemberton], June 12, 1776; 13x7-3/4; Hutchinson, James, 1752-1793
    London, A.L.S. 4p., end. Copy. Difficulty of sending letters. Concerning relatives. Outlines his study of medicine in London under Pott, John and William Hunter, as Fothergill recommended. Concerning American-English difficulties.
  - Letter to [Mrs.] Mary [Stanbury] Pemberton, Philadelphia, June 13, 1776; 13x7-3/4; Hutchinson, James, 1752-1793
    London, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. His studies of medicine. Refers to Fothergill. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Mrs. Katherine Rickey Hutchinson Milnor], June 24, 1776; 13x8; Hutchinson, James, 1752-1793
    London, A.L.S. 2p. Hopes to finish his study of medicine and return home shortly. Refers to Fothergill. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [Mrs.] Katherine [Rickey Hutchinson] Milnor, Bucks County, Sept. 20, 1776; 10x7-1/2; Hutchinson, James, 1752-1793
    London, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Wishes to return home, and will follow Fothergill's advice to return via France.
  - Letter to Alexander Delporte, Paris, Oct. 12, 1776; 9x7-1/4; Crafton & Colson
    London, L. 1p. and add. Introduces James Hutchinson.
  - Letter to Dacosta freres, Nantes, Oct. 12, 1776; 9x7-1/4; Nezian, André
    London, A.L.S. 1p. and add. In French. Introduces James Hutchinson who seeks a boat to America.
  - Letter to James Hutchinson, Oct. 14, 1776; 9-3/4x7-1/2; Barclay, John & Robert
    London, L. 1p. and add. Authorizes him to draw bill of exchange on them if he needs money.
  - Letter to James Hutchinson, Nov. 9, 1776; 9-1/2x8; Fothergill, John, 1712-1780
    A.L.S. 3p. and add. Recommends his return via France, with B. Waterhouse as a companion. Suggests medicine to take with him. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Israel Pemberton, Nov. 10, 1776; 12-1/2x8; Corbyn, Thomas
    London, A.L.S. 2p., end. News of Quakers in England. Concerning James Hutchinson.
  - Letter to [Israel Pemberton], December 5, 1776; 9-1/2x8; Fothergill, John, 1712-1780
    London, A.L. 4P., end. Praises James Hutchinson, and his study of medicine. Comments on the war.
  - Letter to "My honoured Friend", Dec. 9, 1776; 9-1/2x8; Fothergill, John, 1712-1780 [John Penn?]
    London, A.L.S. 1p. Recommends Hutchinson as surgeon for "your Hospital."
  - Letter to Israel Pemberton, Dec. 10, 1776; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Townsend, John, 1757-1826
    London, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Praises James Hutchinson. Refers to John Fothergill.
  - Letter to W[illia]m McAdam, March 24, 1777; 12-1/4x7-3/4; Pemberton, Israel, 1715-1779
    Philadelphia, L. 4p., end. Asks if he would get James Hutchinson's things from the British. Describes items needed for practicing medicine.
  - Letter to And[re]w Elliot, March 25, 1777; 8x6; Pemberton, Israel, 1715-1779
    Philadelphia, A.L. 2p. and and. Asks if he would help get James Hutchinson's things from the British. He needs them to begin practice of medicine.
  - Receipt to James Hutchinson for donation of £10, May 10, 1777; 8x8-1/2; Pennsylvania Hospital
    D.S.: Joseph Hillborn, Treas. 1p. Seal Parchment.
  - Letter to Israel Pemberton, Sept. 15, 1777; 9-1/4x7-1/4; Hutchinson, James, 1752-1793
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Sympathetic letter. Concerning his estate in Germantown and damage sustained while it was used as Gen. Sullivan's head quarters.
  - Letter to Israel Pemberton, Reading, Sept. 16, 1777; 9x7; Hutchinson, James, 1752-1793
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p. and add., end. Friendly letter containing family news.
  - Letter to [Israel Pemberton], Sept. 17, 1777; 8-3/4x7; Hutchinson, James, 1752-1793
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 2p., end. Rain prevented his visiting in Reading.
  - Letter to Israel Pemberton, Sept. 23, 1777; 13x8; Hutchinson, James, 1752-1793
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. Family, friendly letter. Sorrow that he must go to Virginia.
  - Letter to Israel Pemberton, Virginia, Oct. 4, 1777; 9-1/4x7-1/4; Hutchinson, James, 1752-1793
    A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. Family, friendly letter. News of his Germantown house being damaged. News to his fellow prisoners in Virginia.
  - Letter to Israel Pemberton, Virginia, Oct. 5, 1777; 9-1/4x7-1/4; Hutchinson, James, 1752-1793
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. Family, friendly letter.
  - Letter to Israel Pemberton, Virginia, Oct. 29, 1777; 9-1/2x7; Hutchinson, James, 1752-1793
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. Family, friendly letter. Hopes he will soon be set at liberty.
  - Letter to Israel Pemberton, Virginia, Nov. 2-3, 1777; 9-1/4x7-1/4; Hutchinson, James, 1752-1793
  - Letter to Israel Pemberton, Virginia, Nov. 7, 1777; 9-1/2x7-1/4; Hutchinson, James, 1752-1793
  - Letter to Israel Pemberton, Reading, Nov. 19, 1777; 12-3/x7-3/4; Hutchinson, James, 1752-1793
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 1p. and add., end. Have received his letter.
  - Letter to Israel Pemberton, Reading, Nov. 22, 1777; 7-1/4x6; Hutchinson, James, 1752-1793
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. Friendly letter of his family.
  - Letter to Israel Pemberton, Virginia, Nov. 23, 1777; 8-3/4x7; Pemberton, Mary Stanbury
    Philadelphia, A.L.S. 3p. and add., end. Family news. Business news.
  - Appointment of James Hutchinson as senior surgeion to the hospital, Dec. 1, 1777; 11-1/2x8-1/2; Shippen, William, 1736?-1808
  - Marriage licence issued to James Hutchinson and Lydia Biddle, Feb. 18, 1779; 13-1/4x8-1/4; Pennsylvania. Supreme Executive Council
    Philadelphia, Printed D. filled in in ms. S.: Jos. Reed and T. Matlack. 1p. Seal.
  - Letter to Clement Biddle, Philadelphia, Feb. 26, 1779; 12-3/4x7-3/4; Greene, Nathanael, 1742-1786
    Middlebrook, L.S. 2p. and add., end. News of the war and orders from Washington.
  - Letter to General Irwin [James Irvine], March 8, 1784; Hutchinson, James, 1752-1793
    Xerox copy of A.L. in 3rd. P. 2p. and add., end. From original in the Charles Roberts autograph collection, Haverford College, Haverford, Pennsylvania. Concerning four men who were burned by the fire-works accident in Market Street.
  - Letter to James Hutchinson, Secretary to the A. Ph. Society, Aug. 20, 1784; 13x8; Annemours, Charles Francois Adrien le Paulnier, Chevalier d'
    Baltimore, A.L.S.: Chev. D'Anmours. 4p. Presents publication by Hervier on animal magnetism and reports his conversations with Lafayette on magnetism. See APS Trans II, [402].
  - Account with Rodolph Tillier, May 1, 1785; 16x6-1/4; Hutchinson, James, 1752-1793
    Philadelphia, A.D.S.: "Received the above Contents of Mr. Rodolph Tillier May 23rd 1786." 2p. and end. Itemized account for medicines and visits.
  - Indenture to James Hutchinson for land on the Ohio River, May 3, 1785; 13-1/4x8-3/4; Wilkinson, James, 1757-1825
    D.S. 2p.
  - Letter to James Hutchinson, Philadelphia, Nov. 21, 1785; 10x7-3/4; Pettit, Charles, 1736-1806
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Is assured the letters should reach him and hopes they have.
  - Letter to [James Hutchinson], Nov. 25, 1785; 9x7; Bayard, John Bubenheim, 1738-1807
    New York, A.L.S. 4p. Concerning meeting of Congress. Refers to a quotation about Franklin: "the election of Dr. Franklin" would induce Congress to remove to Philadelphia "to avail themselves of His superior Wisdom."
  - Letter to [James] Hutchinson, Dec. 11, 1785; 9x7-1/4; Pettit, Charles, 1736-1806
    New York, A.L.S. 4p. Concerning Morris and his ideas on the bank and taxation. Public business. Refers to Jay.
  - Letter to James Hutchinson, Philadelphia, Dec. 16, 1785; 13-1/4x7-3/4; Pettit, Charles, 1736-1806
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. and add. Forwards a bill for revenue and the bank and hopes M[orri]s will withdraw his bill.
  - Letter to James Hutchinson, Philadelphia, Dec. 17, 1785; 13x7-1/2; Pettit, Charles, 1736-1806
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Concerning his draft of a bill for funding public debt. Refers to Rittenhouse.
  - Letter to [James] Hutchinson, Dec. 18, 1785; 13-1/4x8; Pettit, Charles, 1736-1806
    New York, A.L.S. 3p. Concerning a bill for banking and funding public debt. Refers to [Thomas?] Paine.
  - Letter to [James] Hutchinson, Dec. 23, 1785; 10x7-3/4; Pettit, Charles, 1736-1806
    New York, A.L.S. 3p. Concerning a funding plan for public debt. Refers to R. Morris and his bank plans.
  - Letter to James Hutchinson, Philadelphia, Jan. 1, 1786; 10x7-3/4; Pettit, Charles, 1736-1806
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Has no time to write a serious letter. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to [James] Hutchinson, Aug. 9, 1786; 10x8; Pettit, Charles, 1736-1806
    New York, A.L.S. 4p. Fiscal policy of the U.S. and Pennsylvania. Friendly letter.
  - Letter to James Hutchinson, Philadelphia, Aug. 14, 1786; 10x8; Pettit, Charles, 1736-1806
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Concerning laws on taxation and the public debt. Refers to Monroe.
  - Letter to James Hutchinson, Philadelphia, Nov. 5, 1786; 10x8; Bayard, John Bubenheim, 1738-1807
    New York, A.L.S. 2p. and add. Will keep his seat in Congree for another week, since he is being replaced.
  - Marriage certificate with Mrs.] Sydney E[vans] Howell [Hutchinson], Nov. 30, 1786; 11-1/2x18; Hutchinson, James, 1752-1793
    Philadelphia, D.S.: James Hutchinson and 17 others. 1p. and end. Parchment.
  - Letter to [James Hutchinson?], Dec. 4, 1787; 9-1/4x7-1/2; Banks, Joseph, 1743-1820
    A.L.S. 3p. Thanks for being made member of the APS Sends account of pure iron from South America. Refers to Royal Society. See: APS Minutes, p. 160.